Damián Oscar Amigo

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

www.AmigoDamian.dev
 dam.oscar.amigo@gmail.com
 17667877697
 € Erlangen, Germany

MY GOALS

I am passionate about programming, constantly training myself. Right now, I'm down the road of data analysis with Python. I am looking for a company where I can put myself to the test and continue to increase my knowledge towards my goal of Data Science and AI.

MY STRENGTHS

Excellent organization, skills and abilities to translate the business vision into an effective high-level architecture and strategy. A leader with collaborative skills to create important relationships, required to deliver excellent solutions. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills, lateral thinking, extensive knowledge in many languages (C#, Java, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL) with specialization in Python.

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native German: A2 English: B1

EDUCATION

2000 - 2004 Informatics Engineering University of Lincoln, Bs. As. Argentina

2015 Certification Xamarin Imparted by Microsoft

2024 Data analysis with Google specialization Imparted by Google

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nov. 2021 – Nov.2023 CDMX, México

UNIFIN FINANCIERA

Backend developer

- API development, management and deployment.
- Python, Django REST Framework, Celery, JWT, MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Microsoft Teams, GitLab, GitBucket, Yira, Postman, PgAdmin.
- Agile methodologies SCRUM, Git.
- AWS, GCP, Docker.
- Training for new programmers, code refactoring.
- Debug and identification of errors in real time.
- Monitoring and resolution of incidents.

Nov. 2017 – Jul. 2021 Buenos Aires, Argentina

WORKANA

Web Developer

- Cloud services (AWS).
- Python (Django), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL.
- Excellent debugging skills.
- Program development life cycle.
- Management of web platforms, WP, Prestashop.
- Development of Landing pages, websites and eCommerce.

Nov. 2011 – Jul. 2017 CDMX, México

SPERTA IMAGI

Developer

- Development in C#, PHP, HTML, CSS, JS, MySQL, Python and Java.
- Strong problem solving and reverse engineering.
- Frontend/backend experience in web development.
- Agile methodologies SCRUM, GitHub, Jira.
- Development of APPs for Android.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- As personal project and hobby, I have created a microscopy analysis program, which analyses different protein
 expression surface on different biological tissues and returns the user a data sheet with de different proteins
 contained in the images.
- Another ongoing personal project I'm working on is an automated cryptocurrency trading system. This system
 works with a history of data that is used to make the decision whether it is a good time to sell or buy said
 crypto asset using third-party APIs. I am studying everything related to AWS to take advantage of these tools
 and set up my system there.